Guide to the Laurence and Virginia Judd Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Laurence and Virginia Judd Papers
1943-2001
RG 188
Yale University Divinity School Library
2.5
(5 boxes)
This collection consists primarily of correspondence with family members, missionary colleagues, and supporting churches, which provides documentation of the life and work of Laurence and Virginia Judd. The Judds were Presbyterian missionaries and fraternal workers in Thailand from 1948 to 1970. Laurence was associate director of the Rural Life Department of the Church of Christ in Thailand from 1961 to 1970. Virginia was involved in educational work and the Church of Christ in Thailand Music Committee.
Judd, Laurence C.
Judd, Virginia
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Laurence and Virginia Judd
Biographical / Historical
1920Aug 27 Laurence Cecil Judd born in Houston, TX 1942 LCJ received B.A. from Rice University
194x Virginia Moffat received B.A. from University of Rochester
1942-1944 LCJ secretary of youth work for New Haven Conference of Churches
1944-1946 LCJ pastor of Foxon Congregational Church, East Haven, CT
1945 LCJ and VMJ married; five children
1946 LCJ received B.D. from Yale Divinity School; VMJ also took courses at YDS and at Institute of Far Eastern Studies at Yale
1946-1947 LCJ assistant pastor of Chinese Presbyterian Church of San Francisco, under appt. by the Presbyterian Board of National Missions
1948 LCJ and VMJ arrived in Beijing, under appointment of the Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions, but due to political situation they were transferred to Thailand in December 1948.
1948-1951 Taught at Bangkok Christian College
1951-1953 Administrative and evangelistic work in Pitsanuloke Province, Thailand
1954 LCJ received M.S. from Cornell University
1954-1959 Rural development work in Nan Province
1961 LCJ received Ph.D. from Cornell University
1961-1970 LCJ associate director of Rural Life Department of Church of Christ in Thailand. Department cooperated with government and private agencies serving rural people and assisted church districts and local congregations in developing church and community improvement projects. VMJ assisted in the department program, tutored English, and was active in musical activities in church schools, village churches, national conferences, and the Lampang community music club.
1970-1986 LCJ professor of sociology and director of Asian studies program at Illinois College.
1977-1989 LCJ publications: Chao Rai Thai: Dry Rice Farmers in North Thailand; A Vision to Some; Chao Rai Thai 1987 Update in Perspective; Trends in Rural Development Policy and Programs in Thailand 1947-1987
Scope and Contents
This collection consists primarily of correspondence dating from 1948 to 1971. The different types of correspondence - with family members, with supporting churches, and with missionary colleagues and friends - provide varying perspectives on the life and work of a missionary family in Thailand. Also of interest are various newsletters, reports, and minutes related to the Music Department at Payap College in Chiang Mai, Thailand, and the Music Committee of the Church of Christ in Thailand.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1943-1971
II. Collected Material,1961-1988
III. Biographical Information, 1952,1965, 2001
Missions -- Thailand; Rural development -- Religious aspects -- Christianity; Missionaries; Judd, Laurence C.; Judd, Virginia; Church of Christ in Thailand. Rural Life Dept; Witthayālai Phāyap
- Correspondence, 1943-1971; Series I
  - Family correspondence
    - Letters to family, 1948 -1961 (Box 1, Folder 1-20)
    - Letters to family, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 21-34)
  - General correspondence
    - Letters re. preparation for missionary service and arrival in China: outfit, medical, finances, transportation, etc., 1943-1948 (Box 3, Folder 35-38)
    - Circular letters sent out by Judds, 1948-1963 (Box 3, Folder 39-40)
  - Correspondence with supporting churches
    - First Presbyterian, Auburn, IL, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - First Presbyterian, Bethlehem, PA, 1958-1970 (Box 3, Folder 42-43)
    - First Presbyterian, Cranbury, NJ, 1947-1971 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Westminster Presbyerian, Detroit, MI, 1951-1970 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Detroit Presbyterian, 1956-1971 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - College Hill Presbyterian, Easton, PA, 1947-1971 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - United Presbyterian, East Stroudsburg, PA, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - First Presbyterian, Hallstead, PA, 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Indianola Presbyterian, Columbus, OH, 1947-1970 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - First Presbyterian, Honesdale, PA, 1964-1971 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Trinity United Presbyterian, Mercer, PA, 1954-1971 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Center Presbyterian, Canonsburg, PA, 1952-1971 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Fort Trumbull Presbyterian, United Presbyterian, Milford, CT, 1947-1967 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Noroton Presbyterian, Noroton, CT, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Union Presbyterian, Oxford, PA, 1964-1971 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - First Presbyterian, Richardson, TX, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Lakeshore Presbyterian, St. Clair Shores, MI, 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - First Presbyterian, Wilkes Barre, PA, 1959-1972 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Westminster Presbyterian, Wilkes Barre, PA, 1963-1970 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Second Presbyterian, Wyalusing, PA, 1958-1968 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence to/from others
    - Friends and missionary colleagues
      - Lacy family [Creighton Lacy was roommate of LCJ at YDS], 1948-1965 (Box 4, Folder 62-66)
      - Re. trip to India, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - "China Diaspora" - missionaries who had to leave Ningpo
      - Margaret Budd, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - Charles and Hazel Harken, 1948-1962 (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - Earle and Bernetia Harvey, 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Arthur and Beth March, 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - Bruce and Ruth Morgan, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - Chuck and Kitty Riddle, 1948-1962 (Box 4, Folder 73)
      - Elleroy and Mabelle Smith, 1947-1955 (Box 4, Folder 74)
      - Rev. W. R. O. Taylor, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Yale friends who went to China and elsewhere as missionaries
      - Harry and Grace Brunger, 1949-1962 (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - Frank and Ruth Cooley [includes detailed report of University Christian Fellowships], 1948-1957 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - Hal and Jane Leiper, 1947-1956 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      - Karl and Bobbi Stange, 1955-1963 (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - Sterling and Barbara Whitener, 1946-1963 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Other correspondence
      - C - L (Box 5, Folder 81)
      - P - Z (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Newsletters from YDS friends (Box 5, Folder 83)
      - Newsletters and bulletins re. communist influence, 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 84)
- Collected Material, 1961-1988; Series II
  - Payap College, Music Department newsletters, 1980-1988 (Box 5, Folder 85-86)
  - Church of Christ in Thailand, Music Committee reports and minutes, 1961-1970 (Box 5, Folder 87-89)
  - Booklets re. missions; brochure on Yale-in-China (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - New church contacts, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 91)
- Biographical Information, 1952, 1965, 2001; Series III
  - Biographical sketches of LCJ and VMJ provided by COEMAR, United Presbyterian Church; Marquis Who's Who 2001 article re. LCJ; card with family photograph, 1952, 1965, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 92)